based on true events
根据真实故事改编
Northern California 1958
加州北部 1958
The fifties are grand time ...
五十年代可是段大好时光......
... if you are a man.
......如果你是个男人
I am Dick Dolly I make things up for living.
我叫迪克·诺兰，我靠写东西维持生计
I'm a reporter.
我是名记者
It's the strangest goddammit story that I've ever covered.
这是我从业以来报道过的最他妈离奇的故事
It start the day Margaret Olmprich walk out of her suffocated husband.
故事从玛格丽特·奥布里希离开她那令人窒息的丈夫那天开始
long before it became a fashionable thing to do.
那时单身妈妈还远未流行
Come on, Jane.
走吧, 简
North Beach, San Francisco
北滩，旧金山
Sugar, you've made it, you're at North Beach!
美女，你办到了，你现在在北滩了！
Look at you, Dierdre!
瞧你这身打扮，徳琼！
DeeAnn.
叫我荻安
I know, but I came on this scene, DeeAnn just sound like something my mom would call me.
我冷不丁想到的，荻安像是我妈会给我起的名字
So, are you flipping through all this? are you settled?
那你正到处找房子吗，定下来没？
How is Jane? Well, Jane is well
简好吗？好，挺好的
She is going to this sweet little school, you know it's really hard without her father
她在一所不错的小学就读，你也知道离了父亲她也挺不容易的...
- just don't know we gonna be able to... - Stop.
也不知道我们能不能...... 打住
You better off
你会越过越好的
To be honest, I never like Frank.
实话说吧，我从没喜欢过弗兰克这家伙
You are a bridesmaid.
你可是伴娘之一啊
Exactly, that's why I couldn't say anything.
就是啊，所以不好说风凉话
But  if I see you run off again, I will tell you.
不过如果还有下次的话，我会直言不讳的
Now come on, let's have some fun.
现在嘛，跟我去耍吧
For jazz, check out Hungry i.
想听爵士乐，去饥饿的我夜店
For Italian, Vanessa.
意大利菜，瓦内萨餐厅
For salvation, try the Buddhist Temple.
寻超度，可以试试佛教庙宇
For Art, Six Gallery.
欣赏艺术，就去六号艺廊
Today only show Modern?
今天只有现代派？
Everyone only shows Modern.
大家都只放现代派的
And in basement, they have espresso.
在地下室，他们有意式
Espresso, What's that, is it like whiffer?
意式啥，那是什么东西，烟吗？
You have a lot to learn.
还有很多东西等着你呢
Back then, women didn't live...
那个年代，没一份工作或前途女人怎么过得下去
All she has is her painting in the trunk.
而她全部的家当就是后备箱里的画
...and her daughter in the back seat.
......和后座上的闺女
Good luck.
祝你好运
We don't get many ladies in here.
我们这里没多少女职员
So your husband aproves you working?
那你丈夫同意你出来工作？
My husband and I are seperated.
我和我丈夫分居了
Seperated?
分居?
I realize I have no employment experience, but I really do need this job.
我明白我没有工作经验，不过我真的很需要这份工作
I have a daughter to support.
我有个闺女要养
I am not very good at tool knive and hone, but I do like to paint.
刀之类的工具我不在行，不过我热爱绘画
So I could just show you my portfolio.
所以我把个人画册拿来给你看下
I studied at the Watkins Art Institute, Nashville.
我在纳什维尔的沃特金斯美院上的学
took some illustration classes in New York.
去纽约学的插画
This is a soft pastel I did.
这幅是我的彩笔作品
This is a charcoal portrait.
这幅是碳笔作
You do understand this is a furniture company?
你明白我们只是家具公司吧？
- You see anything like? - I like those over there.
你有看到啥喜欢的? 我喜欢这边的
They are relly neat.
它们真的很漂亮
Your stuff is cute.
你的画很可爱
Thank you.
谢谢
How much?
什么价?
Today's special, two dollars.
今天特价，2美元
- I give you one. - All right.
1美元行吗 好啊
- Go ahead. - Go ahead and have a seat.
过去吧 坐那里去
What's your name?
你叫什么名字?
- My name is Dolly. - Dolly.
我叫多利 多利
- How old are you? - I'm 9 years old.
几岁了? 今年9岁了
Nine years old.
九岁了啊
- Looks like Monet. - Monet?
像莫奈的画 莫奈?
That's hell of a compliment.
真是太过奖了
If I may respectfully disagree, I'm more a traditional Pissarro
如果容我礼貌的唱下反调，我更传统、更像毕沙罗
Come, come a little closer.
来，靠近瞧瞧
See these daring spacing, bold color!
瞧瞧这大胆的构图，生动的色彩！
You wanna touch it?
想摸摸看吗？
Come on, come on, do it.
来嘛，来摸摸看
I don't lay it on thick, you not gonna break it.
我不是吹牛哦，摸是摸不坏的
It's $ 35.
价格35美元
Would you excuse me one second?
你们能等我一会儿吗？
- Here you go. - Thank you.
画给你 谢谢
You're better than spare change.
你赚些零钱太屈才了
Shouldn't sell youself so cheap.
你不该卖这么便宜
Well I'm just glad he like it.
他们喜欢我的画就好
You past that point.
你已经有一定水准了
your heart is in your work.
你的作品洋溢着你的心血
What's your name?
敢问芳名？
Margaret
玛格丽特
What would you rather have? flirting with those girls over there?
那你更愿意什么呢，和那些姑娘打情骂俏？
No, I, like you, Margaret ...
不，我和你一样，玛格丽特......
... Ulbrich.
...... 奥布里希
You know, Margaret Ulbrich, you undervalue yourself.
你知道吗，玛格丽特·奥布里希，你太低估自己了
Let me show you how is done.
让我教你一手
Little girl!
小妹妹!
How would you like your portrait sketched by ...
你想不想让世界著名的湾区女王，玛格丽特·奥布里希给你作幅画?
in mere minutes she capture you soul!
分分钟就能捕获你的神韵！
- Nah. - Why nay?
不要 为什么不呢?
Don't you wish this were you in this beautiful painting?
难道你不想像这被画的漂漂亮亮的吗？
That is me.
这画的是我
And That's me ...
那画的也是我 ......
that starts is me, then mother change it into chinese boy.
这幅画开始时是我，然后妈妈把它改成了中国小男孩
My apology.
那我道歉
I misconstrue the situation.
我完全误会了
I'd better mosey along before Mr. Olbrich comes back, socks me in the eye.
我最好赶在奥布里希先生回来赏我个黑眼圈前溜走吧
Mr. Olbrich is out of the picture
奥布里希先生和我们不是一家人了
- Good evening, Henry! - Mr. Keane!
晚上好， 亨利！ 基恩先生!
Sorry for not calling first.
抱歉没有提前通知你
Let's see, your regular table is ready.
让我瞧瞧，你的老位置空着
Madame, good evening,  follow me.
女士，晚上好啊，这边请
And I don't have to pay,  I'm set because I give a chef a painting.
我不用付钱，因为我赠送了一幅画给厨师
- You know what he said? - What?
你知道他怎么说吗？ 什么?
He said, "no one paints Montmartre like Walter Keane!"
他说：“没人能像沃尔特·基恩那样把蒙马特（巴黎北区）画的这么美”
I can't believe you lived in Paris.
真羡慕你在巴黎呆过
Best time of my life.
我人生中最美的一段时光
I never even on a airplane.
我至今连飞机都没坐过
You have to experience these things.
你得去亲身体验生活
You have to grab on.
你得抓住机会
I want to be a artist, I just went.
我想当艺术家，说走就走
Studied painting at the Beaux Arts.
去了法兰西艺术院学绘画
Live in the left bank studio, survive on bread and wine.
住在左岸的画室里，终日与红酒、面包为伴
You are a romantic.
你是浪漫型的
Damn right you are.
你说的太对了
Of course, walking away from bourgeois things wasn't easy.
当然，抛下富足的生活并不容易
I have to quit my job.
我得辞掉工作
Leave my wife.
离开妻子
Yeah, these choices aren't easy.
做这些抉择并不容易
I never act freely.
我的人生从不自由
I was a daughter, then wife ...
为人女，为人妻......
... then a mother.
...... 然后为人母
All of my paintings are Jane, because she is all I know.
我所有的画都是简，因为她就是我的全部
Don't knock off you work.
别看低自己的作品
You have amazing talent.
你天赋过人
You can look someone, capture them on canvas.
你能打量一个人，然后把他画出来
You can paint people.
你能画人物
I can only paint things.
我只能画风景
Yeah, my street things are ...
恩, 我的街景画......
... charming.
...... 是挺迷人的
But, at the end of day, they are just collections of ...
可是到最后，它们只是一堆楼阁、街道的大合集
Walter, I bet you can paint anything.
沃尔特, 我打赌你什么都能画
When you look at me like that, I could fall a lot hard.
当你用那样的眼神看我，我会狠狠的坠入爱河
I'm sorry.
抱歉我失态了
This just moving really fast.
我们之间发展的太快了
I haven't been on a date in a long time.
我很久都没约过会了
Jane, sweetie, stop wiggling.
简，你别扭来扭去的
Mother, after all these time you must know what my face looks like.
妈妈，这么些年下来你应该对我的脸再熟悉不过了吧
Hey, you canvas is blank.
嘿，你的画布还空着
You can't rush for inspiration.
灵感是强求不来的
Don't bother Mr. Keane, you know creativity come from within.
别烦基恩叔叔，你也知道才思泉涌、由内而外
Don't worry, she is not bothering me.
别担心，她一点都不烦人
Can I ask you a question.
能问你个问题吗
What's that with big crazy eyes?
这大的吓人的眼睛有什么寓意吗？
I believe you can see things in the eyes.
我相信你能从中看到什么
Eye is the window to the soul
眼睛是通往心灵的窗户
Yeah, but you paint two pancakes.
是的，不过你画的两个饼
Way out of proportion.
比例夸张
Eyes are how I express my emotions.
眼睛是我表达自己情感的方式
I always draw them like that.
我总是把它们画成这样
When I was little, I had surgery left me deaf for a period.
我小的时候动过手术，结果失聪了一段时间
I couldn't hear, so I found myself staring.
听不见声音，于是我总是干瞪着眼
And idle on peoples' eyes.
看着别人的眼睛
Walter?
沃尔特?
Hey, I thought that was you!
嘿，我就觉得是你！
I am gald to see you.
很高兴见到你
Hey, any heard back from the city on that setback?
嘿，那个问题你有消息了吗?
My guy really need versions for the forth floor retail.
我的人很需要那个楼层销售的方案
- We will hear from permits by Thursday. - Yeah, that's terrific, I'll tell the architect.
周四就会晓得了 是吗，那太好了，我去告诉设计师
What was that?
那是什么情况？
I didn't want you to know.
我没想让你知道的
I'm in comercial real estate.
我从事房地产生意
You're a realtor?
房地产经纪人？
Yeah, hugely successful realtor, top earner, downtomn office.
恩，事业很成功，收入傲人，市区办公
Three years running.
有三年多了
And you are ashame?
你还难以启齿？
Any blockhead can arrange a sublease.
傻子都可以干这一行
All I ever wanted ...
我一直想的是成为一名靠自己手艺谋生的艺术家
Try to make a clear break, couldn't cut it.
尝试过后却没成功
I am just a sunday painter.
现在我只能做周日画家
Thank you, just come right in here.
谢谢，进来这里吧
Just set it down over here ...
就放在那吧......
- Right here? - Yeah, that's great, I just like to keep it out of the way.
这儿？ 恩，就那，那样不会挡道
This is one of them I'm working on.
这是我还在画的一幅作品
You can see I'm working on it.
还在想着怎么画好
I got the mail.
我收了信
What's wrong?
出什么事了?
Frank wants take Jane away.
弗兰克想把简从我身边夺走
- He say I'm a unfitted mother ... - You're a perfect mother.
他说我是个不称职的母亲...... 你是个完美的母亲
He told the court that she lacks a proper home ...
他跟法庭说简需要个完整的家庭...
... it is beyond my capability as a single mother.
... 而我这个单身母亲是没法给她提供的
Marry me.
嫁给我
Don't think of a reason to say no, I got a million reasons to say yes.
别找借口说不，我可有无数的理由说服你
- I know it makes no sense. - no, it doesn't.
我知道这有点不合常理 是有点
Just think the fun we'll have.
只是想想我们会多开心
I'm gonna to take care of you girls.
我会好好爱护你们母女俩
Margaret, I'm on my knee, come on what do you say? let's get married!
玛格利特，我向你求婚，你答不答应？让我们结婚吧！
We could be at Hawaii by the weekend.
我们周末就可以在夏威夷了
Hawaii, marriage?
夏威夷，结婚？
I don't know, Walter. I'm crazy about you, I'm just really overwhelmed righ now ...
我不知道，沃尔特，我很喜欢你，只是现在我有点不知所措
... why we go to Hawaii, why?
为什么我们要去夏威夷？
Because you're a pricess, you deserve to get married in paradise.
因为你是个公主，你就该在天堂下结婚
You were right, it's paradise.
你说的没错，这真是人间天堂.
Only God could creat these colours.
这色彩只能是上帝的手笔
I knew you would love it.
我就知道你会喜欢
Can we just stay here forever?
我们可以永远待在这吗？
I don't know about forever, but I guess I could arrange for another week.
永远我不敢说，不过多待一星期是我想是可以安排的
That's waterfall, and air is so fresh, you can taste it.
那是瀑布，空气超清新，忍不住尝了下
This is an ancient altar, that's a statue of Kane, the God of Creation.
这是个古老的神坛，那是凯恩的雕像，他是创造之神
I said a prayer to him.
我对他许了个愿
That's Walter and Jane, they build that sand castle together.
那是沃尔特和简，还有他们一起堆的沙堡
Well, these just all happening mighty quick, by the time you moved here ...
这一切都发生得太快了吧，你刚搬过来
... I had two days, you're already married.
我们分开没两天，你就已经嫁人了
Well, I thought there is a void in my life, and Walter fills it.
我想是因为我的人生空了一块，沃尔特正好填上
Walter fills a lot of things, he did every skirt in the acts.
沃尔特填的真是时候，趁虚而入
That's my husband you're talking about.
你说的可是我老公啊
I know, that's why I brought it up.
我知道，所以我才实话实说
I'm not naive.
我不是天真
I am naive, but I know who I married.
好吧我是天真了点，不过我可没胡乱嫁人
Walter can be rush, but he is a good provider, and he is really wonderful with Jane.
沃尔特这事是急了点，不过他经济条件好，而且对简视如己出
We just looking to make a fresh start, I'm a divorcer with a child.
我们只是想重新开始，我一单身母亲带着闺女得现实点
Walter is a blessing.
有沃尔特是我的福气
"You are on a threshold of untold success."
"你正迈向未知的成功之旅"
Its brilliant is about the compostion of spontaneity.
它的高明之处在于构图的自发性
The image has no visual center for attention.
图像本身没有一个视觉吸引点
- It's quite gestural. - Oh definitively, strongly influenced by Tachism.
姿态感很强 说到点子上了，很明显信奉塔希主义
I heard Tab Hunter was in here looking at one.
我听说泰布·亨特来这里时对某幅画表现过兴趣
Well, I am not allow to say.
这嘛，我不方便透露
For Christ!
天杀的
Don't come in here, not now, please ...
别现在进来，好吗......
Ruben, good day, you got a minute?
鲁本，日安，能占用你几分钟吗
Walter, polite to say, the word is appointment.
沃尔特，客气的说你得预约
I can come back later.
我待会儿再来吧
You gonna love my stuff today.
今天带来的画你肯定喜欢
Have I not seen that one before?
那幅画我以前见过吧？
No, that was painted in the fifth arrondissement, this is sixth arrondissement.
不，你看过的那幅画的是第五区，今天这幅画的是第六区
I don't understand. you lived in Paris for a week, how can you still be cranking out paintings?
我不明白了，你在巴黎就待了一周，怎么能画出这么多幅来？
It's all up here, and here.
都印在脑海、心间里呢
That's not going up here.
反正不会上我的墙
Walter, you know we don't go for that representational jazz, you're too literal.
沃尔特，你知道我们不推具象派这种货色，你的画太平庸了
- Art is a fashion. - Yes it is!
艺术是一种潮流 就是啊
People want Kandinsky or Rothko, they don't want goofy street scene.
人们想看的是康定斯基或罗斯科的画，而不是什么傻街景
How about this.
那看看这个如何
Good God, you enter a new period.
天啊，你老树开新枝了
They are my wife's.
这都是我妻子的画
Why are their eyes so big?
怎么眼睛都这么大？
Like they steal jelly beans.
像是偷了果冻豆一般
It's expressionism, truly a recognized.
这是表现主义，一看便知
Well, I'm just glad your two found each other.
很高兴你俩意气相投
- So what do you say? - I say no, it's not art.
那你的意见是？ 我说了不行，这不是艺术
- It's not art? - Like a back of magzine, you know.
不是艺术？ 这就是杂志封底的水准, 你还不明白吗
"Draw a turtle, send a nickel, win the big contest."
"画只海龟，交点报名费，大奖等着你拿"
How dire you? lots of people will like these.
你小看人!很多人都会喜欢这个的
Well, nobody who walks in the door of this gallery.
跟你直说了吧，来我们画廊的顾客肯定不会喜欢
Now, please clear out the clunker before taste police arrive.
好了，现在请收拾你的东西走人，不然人说我的品味降低了
We never break in.
我们永远都出不了名
It's a secret society of gallery owners and critics.
这是个画廊老板和评论家的私密圈子
Who get together for sunday brunch at Sausalito to deciding what's cool.
他们周末聚在苏萨利托吃早午餐时，就决定了潮流风向标
Like McCarthy hearings "I knowing that painter, I banish that painter to nowhere."
就好像麦卡锡的听证会 “恩这个画家我熟，那个画家该滚蛋”
I think people buy art because it touches them.
我觉得人们买艺术品是因为被作品所打动
Yeah, you're living in fairy land.
恩，你还活在童话里
People don't get to discovery anythings, they buy arts because ...
人们不是主动去找寻想要的，他们买艺术品只是跟风而已
Ok, give it up for Cal Jader
好请给卡尔·雅德尔点掌声
Be sure to stick around for 1 am show.
1点的演出欢迎大家继续捧场
Hey Banducci, I love the music tonight, it's aghast.
嗨，班度奇，今晚的音乐很棒，很震撼
Thanks, thank you.
谢谢夸奖
Walter Keane, I'm a painter.
在下沃尔特·基恩，是位画家
I was looking at your walls, they are pretty plain.
我留意到你的墙壁，感觉单调了点
Oh maybe you're right.
你可能说的对
What color would you think?
你觉得那种颜色好？
No, I'm a artist
不，我是位艺术家
I used to base on left bank.
曾在巴黎左岸呆过
Now I relocate to the States, I'm looking for an exhibition venue.
现在回到美国定居，正想找个展览场所
I like my club the way it is.
我喜欢我店现在的样子
The stuff is so hot, don't put it into a museum.
生意正红火呢，可不想把它变成博物馆
OK, I respect that, you're a business man.
恩，我尊重你的意见，你是个生意人
Not a charity.
不是搞慈善的
How about if I rent your walls?
如果我租用你的墙呢？
Walter, Margaret, we're ready.
沃尔特，玛格丽特，准备好就拍了
Ah, an art lover, beautiful!
哈，钟爱艺术的人最美了
What can I do for you sir?
能为你做点什么吗?
I am just looking for the junk
我只是来找洗手间
Thanks.
谢了
Look at that child!
看看那孩子！
She so sad.
她好伤感啊
- Is she poor? - She is forgotten.
穷人孩子？ 孤苦伶仃的样子
Just make me wanna cry.
让我都想哭了
Are you Keane?
你就是基恩?
Yes, I am.
是，正是在下.
You are hell of a painter.
你画得真棒
Thank you, thank you very much.
多谢，多谢你的夸奖
Your work is very powerful.
你的作品很震撼
There is so much emotion in those eyes.
这些眼睛充满了情感
- Is something wrong? - No.
有什么不对吗？ 没有
I didn't realize you mean that waif.
我没意识到你说的是那幅孤儿画
I get it, the artist doesn't want to part with his favorite piece.
我明白了，是画家舍不得他的心爱之作
Oh sweetie, thank you! I love it!
噢，亲爱的，谢谢你，我喜欢！
Hey, Picasso!
嘿，毕加索！
Nice crowd, Huh?
人很多啊，恩？
You wouldn't know from that brown closet you pack me in.
你去那个你打发我的小隔间里看看人多不多
What do you talk about? That plan is thoroughly.
发什么牢骚？不都计划好了
People drink, they gonna relieve themselves.
顾客开怀畅饮，时候到了就得方便
That's insulting.
这是种侮辱
When people see art, they shouldn't think their shit.
人们不该在欣赏艺术的时候还想着拉屎拉尿
Hey, why your use proper language.
嘿，当着女士的面
Hey, there's lady present here.
你嘴巴放干净点
BISTRO BRAWL: BANDUCCI AND ARTIST SLUGFEST
夜店冲突：班度奇和画家大打出手
I have never post a bail before.
我还从来没保过人
Sorry.
对不起
Banducci laugh at our arts, I socked him.
班度奇笑话我俩的画，我就揍了他
Since when do you thin skin?
你啥时变得这么敏感？
Artists have to handle critic.
艺术家得接受批评
I know, I know, you're right.
我知道你说得对
I was at a bad place already.
我心情本来就不好
I had a couple of men, I made some guy believe I painted your big eyes.
我打发了几个家伙，让人以为你的大眼睛是我画的
What?
什么?
I don't understand, why would you do such thing?
我不明白，你为什么要那么做？
It was a misunderstanding.
只是一场误会
And then I didn't want to risk the sell.
然后我不想让生意黄了
Well, don't ever do it again.
好吧，不过绝不要有下次了
Don't give me a hard time, I'm just grabbing my stuff.
别找我麻烦，我只是收拾东西走人
Can you believe it?
你敢相信吗？
We sold out, I don't even have a headliner.
我们满员了，我连压轴演出的都不用请
Hell it's monday!
竟然还是周一！
Walter, we made the front page.
沃尔特，我们上了头版
People are here because they want to see that sappy painting...
人们蜂拥而至只是想看什么破画会让两个男人大打出手
- I'm sick of you, Keane! - I'll see you in court gate!
我烦死你了, 基恩! 我要上法院告你！
- You son of a bitch! I'll sue you ... - I'm sick of you and your paintings!
你个龟儿子!我要去告你 我烦死你和你的画了!
I'll sue you for slander!
我要告你诽谤!
Walter Keane was not a subtle man.
沃尔特·基恩不是个低调的人
But subtle dosen't sell.
不过低调可没人买账
Yes sir, that was quite a lot horse shit you just relate out there.
你行啊，你那番话真够狠的
I'm Dick Nolan, Examiner.
在下迪克·诺兰，考察家报
Hey pal, I don't lose any sleep. I eat stuff from spoon.
嘿老兄，我专写八卦，随时都可联系我
Give me something to write about. my column.
有料就向我报！我的专栏
I thought you were only doing celebrities
我以为你只写名人的东西
Banducci is famous, and you hit him.
班度奇是个名人，而你揍了他
So you're a celebrity worth snoop.
所以你现在也是个值得八卦的名人了
Buy me a drink.
请我喝一杯吧
Hi, Gary, I like a ... , and my friend will have the same.
嗨，加里，给我上杯好酒，我朋友也要一样的
So, Walter, tell me about your work.
那么沃尔特，跟我说说你的作品吧
When I was in Paris ...
过去我还在巴黎时 ......
No, no jesus not those.
不，不是讲那些
I mean the little hobo kids.
我指的是那些“流浪儿”
Wake up.
醒醒
You were a hit.
你出名了
What a night.
今晚赚翻了
I sold out all your .
我卖光了你的大眼睛
$ 200.
200块
They adore you!
他们可喜欢你的画了！
Because of that article, the joint was packed.
因为那篇报道，夜店人满为患
There are famous journalists, sold all of it. I need more paintings!
来了很多著名记者，画作一抢而空，我需要更多的画！
This is a opportunity, we gonna make a cracker jack team!
这是个大好机会，我们会组成完美团队
Me show them in the club, you got here doing what you love.
我驻扎夜店推广，你在家倾情创作
Get out of here.
快拿开
I love you.
我爱你
The eyes are so powerful.
这些眼睛真摄魂
You know a poet once said ...
知道吗，有位诗人曾经说到眼睛是通向心灵的窗户
That's why I paint them so big, I always done it that way.
所以我才把它们画这么大，这是我的一贯作风
If you're interested in that style, one of new pieces.
如果你对这种画风感兴趣，我最新的一幅作品
I have a little blond girl in a yellow dress.
画的是一个身着黄衣的金发小姑娘
It'll tear you heart out.
会让你心都碎了
Baby, what're you doing here?
宝贝，你来这做什么？
Why are you lying?
你为什么要撒谎？
Excuse me.
抱歉失陪一会儿
You are taking credit for something that isn't yours.
赞赏的是我的作品，你干嘛冒名顶替
I'm just trying close a deal.
我只是想做成生意
These children are part of my being.
这些孩子是我生命的一部分
I must say, you know buyers would pay more if they meet the painter.
我只是为了卖画，你也知道能和画家面对面的话，买家会愿意下血本
They couldn't meet me because you told me to stay home.
他们见不到我是因为你让我待在家里
Look, we're making money.
冷静点，只要能赚钱
Your pocket, my pocket, where is the difference?
你赚的，我赚的，有分别吗？
You're taking this so lightly.
你根本不把这当回事
Not at all, this is not about ego.
哪有，我不是想拔高自己
You want to say you did the street scene, that's fine.
你如果想说街景是你画的，我没意见
I don't care,say a monkey painted them.
说是猴子画的我也不在乎
Oh God, you could just dash your word without any emotional connection.
天啊，你可以不加思索就说出这些话来
Honey, I just wanna share it with the world.
宝贝，我只是想让全世界都看到我们的画
Would you rather your children pouting in closet ...
你想让自己的孩子蜗居过苦日子还是住大房子衣食无忧
Who is that man?
这人什么来头？
That is Dino Olivetti.
那是迪诺·奥利维蒂
Don't even think about, Walter, he doeson't speak  lack of english.
沃尔特，别想高攀，他不会说英语
Mr Olivetti is enchanted by the painting, he would like to know who is the artist.
奥利维蒂先生被这幅画迷住了，他想见识一下画家本人
I am.
在下就是
Five grands!
五打五千!
We made  5000 dollors!
我们赚了5000啊！
That was not even for one of your good ones.
还不是你的佳作就买了5000
Don't you mean your good one?
你指的是你的佳作吧?
No!
不是!
Our, one of our good ones.
我们的，是我们的佳作之一.
We now hanging in the collection of italian industrialist Dino Olivetti.
我们的画现在被意大利企业家迪诺·奥利维蒂收藏了
With his patronize comes credibility.
他买我们的画就等于一种认可
With credibility, comes respect.
有了这种认可，名望随之而来
What about honesty?
那实情呢？
All our paintings say Keane.
我们的画都签的是基恩
I'm Keane, you're Keane.
我是基恩，你也是基恩
From now on, we're one of the same.
从今往后，我们不分彼此
My source tell me the mayor expect big surprise today.
有人向我爆料说市长今天预期会收到个大惊喜
On behalf of the children of the world, I pesent this painting ...
代表全世界的儿童，我把这幅画赠与旧金山市长
My man on the street tells me Soviet ambassador in town as speak.
外面有人通知我苏联大使正在来访
In the interest of peace throught culture ...
以文化传递和平我把这幅画赠与苏联人民
The Purple Onion, 21:30, Joan Crawford have dinner reservation.
晚上9点半，琼·克劳福德在紫洋葱预订了位子
Mrs. Crawford, in recognition of your cinematic craft ...
克劳福德女士，为了向你的表演致敬我们赠送这幅肖像画给你!
The cat is out of the bag.
这秘密不新鲜了
I can revail our local luminary Walter Kean is open his own gallery.
我们本地的名人沃尔特·基恩的个人画廊即将开馆
Ruben gonna choke when he see these.
鲁本看到这还不得气死
I remember my mom painted that.
我记得是我妈画的
Are you sure? that would been awhile ago.
你确信？那可是好久以前的事了
Sure it is.
我记得很清楚
It was at old apartment you had me sit still in the kitchen.
是在过去公寓的厨房里画的我
No, sweetie, you're comfused. I painted that.
不对，乖乖，你搞错了，这是我画的
No, mother did, I wear my wool dress.
不是，是我妈画的，我穿的那件羊毛衫
Lots of girls have that dress.
很多小女生都穿那种衣服
You have a good eye.
你眼力不错
I painted it, and try to mimic your mom's style
其实我是照你妈妈的风格画的
You know, the style she used to paint.
你记得吗，你妈过去的绘画风格
You did a really good job.
那你真是学得很像
Hello.
你好
I'm sorry, I've never done this before.
抱歉，我从没做过这个
I was raised Methodist, so if that's a problem I could go.
我从小就接受的是卫理公会，如果这不允许我就走
No no, please, we don't chase people away.
不会，请坐吧，我们不会赶人走的
What is troubling you?
何事困扰着你？
I lie to my child.
我对自己的孩子撒谎
Why did you do that?
你为什么那样做？
My husband he pressure me to do it.
我丈夫唆使我去干的
I just never lie to her, I am not that kind of person.
我从没对她撒过谎，我不是那种人
Is your husban that kind of person?
那你丈夫是吗？
I don't think him that way.
我不那样看他
He likes to tell stories, and he exaggerates about.
他喜欢讲讲故事，吹吹牛什么的
He is a good man.
他本质不坏
He just try to save enough money to buy a house for the family.
他只是想攒够钱好买我们自己的房子
But what about the chlid, will this lie bring harm to her?
那孩子呢？这谎言会给她带来伤害吗？
Harm? no, no.
伤害? 不, 不会
I'm just looking for some answers.
我只是找人开解下我
Well, the modern world is a complex place.
这么说吧，现代社会错综复杂
Occasionally, children may need to be sheltered from certain truth.
有时候，不说真相的目的是为了保护孩子
No, it's not like ...
不是，不是的 ......
It sounds if your husband is to try to make the best of ...
听起来你丈夫只想尽力改善家人的处境罢了
You were raised Christian, you know we were taught ...
你从小接触基督教义，知道主教导我们男人是一家之主
Perhaps  you should trust his judgement.
或许你该相信他的判断
Keane Gallery, Opening Night, 1960
基恩画廊， 开馆之夜， 1960年
I think it's creepy, modern, and amateurish.
我觉得这画现代了点，业余了点，还有点吓人
Exactly.
一语中的
I love it.
我就喜欢这种画
We got here early, we are three.
我们3个早就到了
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey, baby! killer party, it's happening
嘿，宝贝，很棒的聚会，梦想成真了
So, where is your stuff?
你的画在哪？
We decided this just be Walter show.
我们决定做沃尔特的个人展
Well, he did? why would he do that?
是吗?他为什么要这样？
Oh, because Walter is more established.
恩，因为沃尔特比较成熟老练
Strange you know, Walter doesn't really strike me ...
有点怪啊，我真不觉得沃尔特会是去画楚楚可怜孤儿的类型
It's really good to see you.
见到你很高兴
Thank you for coming.
感谢前来捧场
Your husband's quite a talent.
你丈夫真有才华
Do you paint too?
你也作画吗？
I don't know.
我不知道
I'm curious about your technique.
我对你的技巧很感兴趣
How long that piece take to excute?
画好那幅画要多长时间？
Probably a month.
一个月左右吧
First, thinking, sketching, then the time just me and oil.
先是构思，然后绘草图，剩下嘛就是我和油画颜料的亲密时刻了
Oil? but is it acrylics?
油画颜料？那不是用的丙烯颜料吗？
That? yeah!
哦，那幅啊
It's just like a jumbo ideas rattling aroung in my brain.
我的脑子里总是有各种点子钻来钻去
So where did you get your ideas?
那你的点子都是从哪来的？
What do you mean?
你的意思是？
I mean why are they all images of the children?
我想知道为什么画的都是小孩子？
May I remind you, Mrs. Rogers,  you sworn under the oath.
罗杰斯女士，我要提醒你，你可是宣过誓的
Mrs Rogers, you testify that ...
罗杰斯女士，你的证词说
When you met Jason Bailey Crowley, he's been talking to a man at the bar.
当你见到杰森·贝利·克劳利时，他正和酒吧里的一个人交谈
I don't understand.
你想说明什么?
Couldn't it be just some stranger who just struck a conversation with Mr. bailey?
会不会只是个陌生人刚好和贝利先生谈上了呢？
- No! - Thank you, Mrs. Roger, that would be all.
不是的 谢谢, 罗杰斯女士，我的问题问完了
Perry Mason  will return after this.
稍后请继续收看《佩里·梅森》
New York Times art critic John Canaday ...
纽约时报艺术评论家约翰·卡纳迪以专业眼光剖析沃尔特·基恩的创作
Keane's work is completely without distinction.
基恩的作品完全模板化
He is not a member of society western artists.
西方艺术界里根本没有他的一席之地
He's won no awards.
他从未获得任何奖项
He's only known to others for his appearence in certain newspaper's gossip columns.
仅仅是上过某报纸的八卦板块才为人所知
Mr. Keane is why society need critics.
基恩先生正是为何社会大众需要评论家来保护他们不受艺术糟粕的荼毒
Mom!
妈!
Mom, can I come in?
妈，我可以进来吗？
No, you can't, mom is busy right now.
不，别进来，我现在正忙
What're you doing?
你在干嘛啊？
Jane, sweetie, come.
简，乖乖，过来
You need to respect your mother's privacy.
你得尊重你妈的个人空间
Sometimes grown-up need their own time.
有时大人不希望被打扰
Is that the  icecream truck?
是卖冰淇淋的吗？
Go get youself a ...
去给自己买个吧......
Out of this world!
世间少有啊!
I don't know.
我不知道
I'm not comfortable with this, Jane and I were really close, now ...
这一切让我有些不自在，我和简过去亲密无间，可现在 ......
Jane is fine.
简很好
She is eating icecream, she hasn't assume she even has a college fund.
有冰淇淋吃，不过还得指望我们给她搞定大学学费啊
Maybe I'm just light-headed from all this turpentine ...
或许我被这挥之不去的松脂味熏得有点心烦意乱
I need you help.
你得帮帮我
I want to go on television to defend our art.
我想上电视去为我们的艺术辩护
Wait, you going on the television?
等等，你要上电视去？
Yeah, but what am I gonna say?
恩，不过我该说些什么？
Meaning what compells me to painted these things?
重点是什么驱使我去创作这些画？
Maybe you have a unhealthy obession with little girls.
或许你病态的迷恋上了小女孩
- Cute. - I'm sorry.
好点子！ 对不起
Looks like "you pin youself into a corner"
看上去你把自己逼上了绝路
Yeah, you want heat this winter, help me out.
是啊，你想冬天有暖气的话，就给我想想办法
Walter, art is personal.
沃尔特，艺术是个人的表达
What compells a grown man to paint a picture like this?
是什么驱使一个成年人去画这样的画？
Because I grew up surrounded by six sisters.
因为我从小与六姐妹一同成长
I grew up in a orphanage.
我成长在孤儿院
I lived at a world where adult had vanished ...
我生活在一个大人销声匿迹由小孩和小猫主宰的荒芜大地？
What about your street scenes? why did you paint these?
那你的街景画呢？你为什么选择画它们?
Well I lived it, I experienced it.
因为我活在其中，亲身经历过
Was it all sunlight dappled streets and flower venders?
走到哪都是点缀着阳光和花店的街道？
Of course not.
当然不是
It was after war.
那可是战后
There was destruction everywhere.
到处都是残垣断壁
I traveled continent, the ravages were horrifying.
我走遍大陆，破坏令人发指
My psyche was scarred in my art student days.
给我艺术学生的心灵留下了创伤
Nothing in my life has ever made such a impact as the sight of children.
没有什么能像孩子的影像一样对我人生带来如此大的冲击
The war racked innocents without parents, without home.
那些被战火夺去父母和家园的无辜孩子
Fighting over garbage.
争相抢夺垃圾
That's when my life as a painter began at earliest.
那就是我画家生涯开始的起点
From then on, I painted lost children with big eyes.
从那时起，我就开始创作各种大眼睛的孤儿
Those eyes forever will retain their haunting quality
这些大眼睛会让人刻骨铭心，永生难忘
How many sales today?
今天卖了多少？
Sales? none with this crowd.
就这群人，会卖得出去？
Those people all lowly looks, they can't afford these paintings.
这些都是凑热闹的穷鬼，可买不起这里的画
But we have been giving away a lot of posters.
不过海报倒是发出去不少
Craziest thing!
我干过最疯狂的事!
I started charging for the posters.
我开始卖海报
First a nickel, then a dime, yes, it's cool!
一开始5分，然后1毛，恩，这点子绝了！
But, then it got me thinking, would you rather sell one $ 500 painting ...
不过，我又再想了想，你是愿意卖一张500美元的画还是一百万张便宜的印刷海报？
See, folks don't care it's a copy.
你看，人们不在乎它是不是印刷的
They just want art that touches them.
只要能表示他们懂点艺术
Then we could sell it to anywhere.
然后我们可以四处开花
Eeverywhere!
卖到世界上的任一个角落！
Lana Del Rey - Big Eyes ... I used to think I could trust you.
拉娜·德雷的同名主题曲 ...... 我曾以为可以信任你
I was your woman.
我是你的女人
You were my knight
你是我的骑士
shining companion.
光彩照人的伴侣
To my surprise, my loves demise.
可没想到，给我的爱送终的
Was his own greed and lullaby.
是他的贪婪和花言巧语
With your big eyes, and your big lies.
用你的大眼睛，和你的弥天大谎
With your big eyes, and your big lies ...
用你的大眼睛，和你的弥天大谎 ......
Stinks here, you should open a window.
味挺大的，你该打开窗户透透气
What time is it?
现在几点了？
6:30.
六点半
What you got back there? let me see.
你那画的是什么？让我瞧瞧
Walter, it's personal.
沃尔特，这是给我自己画的
Personal, we married! we're not suppose to have secret from each other.
你自己的？我们是夫妻，不该对对方有所隐瞒
Put it out there.
快拿出来
It's completely diferent style.
这完全是另一种风格
Yes, it is.
的确是啊
Kind of looks like you.
有点像你
Well, it's a self portrait.
恩，是自画像
How am I gonna explain that?
这个我该如何解释？
I was thinking that ...
我在考虑 ......
... maybe I could sigh it myself.
... 或许签我自己的名字
That sounds a bit comfusing? doesn't it?
那听上去让人分不清楚啊，不是吗？
Keane means me.
‘基恩’指的是我
I know, but when people asks me if I paint ...
我明白，可当有人问我是否也作画我不知该如何应答
It would be nice to have a pride being able to say that's mine.
如果能挺起胸膛说那是我画的，不是很好吗
Who you tells about "Big Eyes"?
你跟谁说了大眼睛的事？
Nobody.
谁也没说
If you tell anyone ...
如果你跟任何人讲半个字我们的努力就全白费了
You wanna give back the money?
你想把钱都退回去？
- We could become Fraud! - I know!
我们会成为诈骗犯！ 我明白！
My God, I know, I live with this every minute of my life.
老天啊，我明白，我无时无刻不在提醒自己
I hold my end of the bargain, I have not told anyone.
我保守我的诺言，从未告诉任何人
Please, just let me handle this.
求你了，这个就交给我来应付
I don't know you painted, Margeret.
玛格丽特，我没想到你也作画
Yeah, we don't know about that.
恩，大家都蒙在鼓里
Sadly, people don't buy lady art.
很不幸，没人会买女人的艺术品
What about Georgia O'Keeffe?
乔治亚·欧姬芙不是个例外吗？
So, Margaret, where did you get your ideas?
那么玛格丽特，你从哪获取灵感？
From the world around me ...
从我身边的一切我钟爱莫迪里阿尼
"Monti" ... what?
"莫迪" ... 谁啊?
For Christ's sake, Margaret!
天啊，玛格丽特！
Dick writes gossip column.
迪克写的是八卦专栏
Stick to the family angle.
就讲讲家庭方面的内容
Get a angle over little Janey over here.
给小简儿也写几句吧
What a talent!
小有天赋哦！
Look at these Keanes!
瞧我们这一家子！
When you cut open our veins, we bleed oil!
你要是切开我们的血管，流出来的都是颜料！
Ah, little treat.
啊，锦上添花
The forth member of the painting Keane.
我们基恩家的第四名画家
Lily, sweetie, how are you?
莉莉宝贝，今天过得好吗？
I'm fine dad, I lost a tooth.
爸爸，我掉了颗牙，其他一切都好
Really?
真的啊?
You getting into a fight?
你和人打架了？
No, it fell out.
没有，它自己掉的
Well, is the tooth fairy something I have to deal with? or your mom alreay handled it?
那么需要我出面对付牙仙，还是你妈已经解决了？
She handled it.
妈妈已经解决了
Good, good, good!
好，太好了!
Janey, come, show her the kids room.
简，过来，带她参观下你的房间
And then you girls can join the fun.
然后你们就自娱自乐吧
Hey, Walter, you never told me you had another daughter.
嘿，沃尔特，你从没告诉我你还有个女儿
Didn't I? sure.
我没说吗？可能吧
Lily is from my first marriage.
莉莉是我和前妻生的
Excuse me, sorry, excuse me.
抱歉失陪一下
Walter, may I have a word with you?
沃尔特，能和你说几句吗？
- What is going on in here? - That's Lily.
这到底是怎么一回事? 莉莉我女儿啊
I'm sure mentioned her.
我跟你提过吧
No, you didn't.
没有，你没说过
- Is she moving in? - No.
她要搬来吗？ 不会
Her mother has gone to Vegas for the weekend.
她妈这周末去拉斯维加斯了
I supposed to have her once a month ...
我本来应该每个月都带她一次的不过她妈不愿意
How could you lie about something so big?
你怎么可以隐瞒这么大的事？
- Oh she is a very sweet girl. - I'm sure she is.
她是个乖女儿 我相信她是
Well I put up with your daughter, never said a peep.
我跟你女儿生活了这么久，有抱怨过一句吗
I'm gonna pretend you didn't say that.
我就当你没说过这句话
I'm sorry.
我道歉
Please, let's just get through this.
好了，把采访做完再说吧
... Walter Keane and Paul Gauguin have a lot in common.
会指出沃尔特·基恩和保罗·高更有很多相似之处
Both walk away from a career to travel the globe ...
两人都放弃既成的事业去全球游学 ......
I've learn a lot of famous personalities.
我接触过许多名流人士
Only a certain type of creature can live in that spotlight.
只有一小类人能适应镁光灯下的生活
Walter had a chops.
沃尔特是得心应手
Margaret not so much.
玛格丽特却束手束脚
- I painted that. - really?
这是我画的 真的吗?
It's very evocative.
很能唤起人的情感
sensual.
也很性感
You're so mystery.
你真神秘啊
Yes, we don't use my name since people don't ...
恩，不用我的全名是因为人们不把女人的艺术品当回事
MDH is my initials.
MDH是我名字的首写字母
And more, I'm really interested in numerology, you know 7 is a really good number.
多说几句，我对命理学非常感兴趣，你知道7是个幸运数字吗？
7?
7?
Luckily, my main name is Margaret Doris Hawkins
凑巧的是，我的全名是玛格丽特·多莉丝·霍金斯
"M" is the 13 letter of the alphabet, "D" is 4, "H" 8.
"M" 是字母表里的第13个字母, "D" 是第4个, "H" 第8个
And you add that up 1 and 3 in 13 ...
你可以把13里的1和3相加 ......
an orgy of color!
一场色彩的狂欢！
Excuse me.
失陪一下
Which makes 4 plus 4 plus 8 equal 16.
那么就可以用4加上4，再加上8，得到16
And 1 plus 6 equal 7.
然后1加6，得到7
Magrate, one second?
玛格丽特，借一步说话？
Good God, what did you think about? longer vision?
天啊，你都想些什么东西啊，忘了远景了？
Could you please help the world and shut your mouth.
你不说话天塌不下来
The only number you want in his head  ... is the price.
你想让他记住的唯一数字 ...... 就是标价
Two nuts fell from the same tree.
一家两口都是疯子
It's insufferable.
让人难以忍受
Why are we starving while they print money?
凭什么他们赚的盆满钵溢而我们却毛都没有
Because that's how genius sells paintings.
因为他们的卖画方法太天才了
And they sell pictures of the paintings, then they sell postcard of the pictures of the paintings.
他们不但卖画作的印刷品，还卖印有印刷品图案的明信片
I bet I could bang one out in 10 minutes.
我打包票这画我10分钟就能整一幅
Wouldn't you have to dealt with the sincerity.
难道你不怕被人识破是赝品？
Well the costumer wouldn't notice.
消费者哪会分的出来
Christ ... it's a movement.
老天 ...... 蔚然成风了
KEANE TAKES ON ART WORLD
基恩书写艺术新篇章
The Man Behind The Eyes
大眼睛的创作人
ARITST KING KEANE
艺术界新贵 基恩
Woodside, California 1963
伍德赛德，加州 1963年
My God! I thought I had the wrong address.
老天，我还以为走错门了
I know it's a really long drive.
我这路途是比较远
Honestly I can't believe I live here.
实话说我都不敢相信住在这里
I know.
我明白
- You got two acres. - A pool, Five bedrooms.
你这房子得有2英亩吧 一个游泳池，5间卧室
I thought it was excessive.
我认为有点大得离谱
Since there is only three of us here.
因为就我们3个人住在这
Been so long since I see you.
都有好久没见你了
I know
是啊
North beach is 30 miles, might as well be 300.
这距北滩30英里，感觉上好像有300英里
Well, you probably busy hanging out with all your new rich buddies.
你是不是整天忙于应酬那些新交的富人朋友啊
Please! those are Walter's friends.
饶了我吧！那些是沃尔特的朋友
He brings people by.
他经常带人来
The Beach Boys came by.
‘海滩男孩’来过这
Are you hungry?
你饿不饿？
I'm thirsty.
有点渴
When I moved in, I thought a wet bar is kind extravagant.
刚搬来时，我觉得这个小吧台有点奢侈多余了
But you would be surprise how much issues can get out of it.
不过你会惊讶它有多好使
So how is Walter?
那谈谈沃尔特吧？
He couldn't be happier.
他再开心不过了
He has everything he's ever dreamed of.
他梦想要的全都有了
So do you, fabulous!
你也一样，真让人羡慕
Is that your arts studio?
那边是你的画室？
- You don't want to go in there. - I wanna take a peek.
你可不想去那 我想瞅一眼
I want to see what work phase of wildly successful artist looks like.
我想看看巨成功的艺术家是如何工作的
No no no...
别，别去 ......
DeeAnn, Please do not go down there.
荻安，请别下去好吗
You can't go in there.
你不可以进去
Walter paints here too.
这也是沃尔特的画室
Is Walter home now?
沃尔特现在在家吗？
What the hell is going on?
这是搞什么啊？
Nothing.
没什么
I just invite DeeAnn over.
我只是请荻安过来看看
You know I don't like anyone seeing my work before it's done.
你知道我不喜欢让人看到没完工的画作
You and your all none representation crap are fraud!
你和你的作品都是骗人的垃圾！
Shut up, you're so full of shit! Walter.
闭上你的臭嘴，沃尔特！
Get out of my house ...
滚出我的宅子 滚出我的豪宅!
Go back selling your sculpture ...
滚去码头向渔夫兜售你的垃圾吧！
Fuck you!
你去死!
I don't want her ever invited here.
我再也不想看到她来
I won't.
我不会了
- All right Jane, I'm get to work. - Can I come?
好了，简，我得开工了 我可以跟着去吗?
No, I can't ever come.
我知道，我永远都不能去
No, I shouldn't even ask.
其实我根本就不该问的
How did you get in here?
你是怎么溜进来的？
Didn't you hear that there is no visitors.
你没听过吗，这里谢绝访客
This is what it comes to, huh!
命运还真是作弄人啊
You're the only living soul I can tell my secret to.
你现在是我唯一可以倾述秘密的生物
Well, I painted them.
那我坦白，它们都是我画的
I did ... every single one of them.
它们一个个 ...... 都是我画的
Every "Big Eyes".
每一幅大眼睛
Me.
我画的
But no one will ever know but you.
可是除了你没人会知道
I'm gonna paint another one right now.
我现在又要动手再画一幅
Take Walter off ...
要是沃尔特在这的话肯定会说我打算画一个对着狗狗自言自语的小疯婆子了
Productive day today.
今天收获不小
Stumble on some hot gossip.
碰上新鲜出炉的传闻
Madame Chiang Kai-shek is coming to town ...
从台北直飞的蒋介石夫人要来我们这里
I think we should present her with a painting, get Dick to flack it.
我想我们得赠送幅画给她，找迪克来报道
Well, hell with Dick, I met a new guy at UPI
噢，找迪克干嘛，我新结识了一个合众国际社的伙计
Maybe she'll like one of your street scenes.
她没准喜欢你画的某一幅街景呢
Yeah, I don't know.
是吗，我拿不准
I thought you could rip off a doodler of china town with a cute little girl.
我觉得你可以描个唐人街的背景加上个可爱的小女孩
Sort of big eye slanting eye thing.
大眼睛稍微画弯点就成
No.
不行
She is a dignitary.
她可是个政要
She deserve a piece come straight from you.
你的亲笔大作才配的上她
You think?
你真这么认为?
Maybe you're right.
你可能对
She probably doesn't has a Parisian street scene hanging in her palace.
她的宫殿里也许就缺少一幅巴黎的街景画
Unless Madame Chiang Kai-shek already has a S. Cenic.
除非蒋介石夫人恰好已经有了一幅申景华的作品
- What's that? - A S.Cenic.
申景华是谁? 那位画家啊
That's the painter that painted all your early work.
那位画了你之前所有作品的画家
It's scenic.
你说的实景画吧
That's my nickname in Paris.
那是我在巴黎时的绰号
All my art school pals love my scenic view so much.
我在美院的同学都很喜欢我画的实景画
They call me, well they couldn't pronouce properly ...
他们见到我就会提实景画，当然由于他们发音不准叫着叫着就成了申景华
The more you lie, the smaller you seem.
你越是撒谎，就越显得渺小
How dare you accused me of lying?
你怎么可以指责我撒谎？
I'm proud of my early scenics.
我对我早期画的实景画相当自豪
Then why did you painted over the name?
那你为什么只把名字画掉？
Piece of advice ...
给你个忠告水溶性的颜料涂在哪都是废的
... I'm just flay right off.
...... 我一刮就掉了
You sound like crazy for God's sake.
你尽说什么疯话啊？
You see me paint.
你见过我画画
No, I haven't
没有，我没见过
I always thought ... I had ...
我一直以为 ...... 我见过 ......
... but it's like a mirage.
...... 不过就像海市蜃楼
I'm in distance, you look like a painter.
我从远处看，你像个画家
Up close, there is not much there.
等一走近，烟消云散无影踪
I've been to Paris!
我去过巴黎！
I studied at the Beaux Arts!
我在法兰西艺术院上的学！
At grande Chaumiere!
还上过大茅屋学院！
I spent hours and hours at the Louvre staring at the great of the masters!
我在卢浮宫无数次的观摩各种大师的伟大作品！
Have you even been to Paris?
你根本就没去过巴黎吧？
I wanted it, I so wanted to become a artist, just never turn out so well.
我是想，我太想成为艺术家了，可总是事与愿违
I don't want you sleep here any longer.
我请你以后都别在来这里睡觉了
There are three extra bedroom in this house, go pick one.
还有三间空出来的卧室任你挑呢
- How many more this under back? - I don't know, maybe 3000?
后面还有多少货？ 我不清楚，可能3000张吧？
- Does the printer ... - Excuse me, Mrs.
那个印刷厂 ...... 女士，我想问下
- How much this painting? - Go! what do I pay you for?
这幅画的价格？ 快去，我请你是干嘛的？
Not even one of mine, one of hers.
又是她的，我的画一幅都没人要
1964 New York World's Fair Construction Races Toward April Opening
1964年纽约世博会
This doesn't change anything.
这可改变不了什么
- I know the truth. - Oh who cares?
我知道了你的真面目 噢，谁在乎啊?
Maybe it's time to shake things off, start putting my name under the MDHs.
或许是时候进行些调整了，该把MDH的画都签成我的名字
No.
不行
Absolutely not, I already hate myself giving you the waifs.
别做梦了，把“孤儿”给你已经让我悔恨万分
Quiet!
小声点！
- Don't raise your voice. - I will talk as loud as I want.
别讲那么大声 从今往后我讲多大声你管不着
No, you won't, or I have you whacked.
你想都别想，不然就要你好看
What?
你说什么？
If you tell anyone, I'll have you taking ...
如果你敢告诉任何人，我就找人收拾了你
I know people, remember Banducci's cousin? liquor wholesaler.
我人脉广，还记得班度奇的侄子吗？那个卖酒的
Are you threatening me?
你这是威胁我?
Fine, kill me.
好吧，杀了我
My God, I keep our secret for years, never once ...
天啊，我守口如瓶这么多年，从未有一次 ......
You know how hard this is been for me?
你能体会我有多不容易吗？
I don't have any friends.
我没有一个朋友
I lie to my own child.
对自己的孩子撒谎
Life imitating art, a crying Keane.
这就是人生如艺啊，哈，一个流泪的基恩
Walter, what do you want?
沃尔特，你到底想要什么？
Everything was your calculated.
一切都在你的算计之中
We're back where we have our first date.
我们又回到初次约会的地点
I don't deny I need you, you're the one with the gift.
我不否认我需要你，你才是有天赋的那个人
Now there is a shot ...
现在有一个大好机会 ......
I'm shaking, I'm so exciting!
我兴奋都发抖了
The New York World's Fair.
纽约世博会
70 millions visitors.
预计七千万游客
Opening day I unveil my master piece.
开园那天我将揭示我的宏伟大作
- What master piece? - Exact.
什么宏伟大作？ 问得太对了
What have we been listening all this time?
我们一直以来听得最多的是什么？
Da Vinci has his Mona Lisa, Renoir has his Boatmen's lunch.
达芬奇有他的蒙娜丽莎，雷诺阿的船上的午宴
Where is my defining statement?
我的留名大作在哪？
You sound insane.
你有点疯了吧
Artist doesn't just annouce his master piece.
艺术家怎么可以自以为是钦定自己的名作
Why not?
怎么不行？
Didn't Michelangelo know he is hitting a home run when he's on his back painting Sistine Chapel?
米开朗基罗挥汗如雨的绘制创世纪时，他会不知道自己留下的将是传世神作？
That take him four years.
那可花了他整整四年
But there is the best part.
最好的部分我还没说呢
It's for Unicef!
这是给联合国儿童基金会的
Unicef sponsors the hall of education.
联合国儿童基金会赞助的教育馆
We can finally give back to the children of the world.
我们终于可以给全世界孩子做点贡献了
WORLD'S FAIR REPORT WITH LOWELL THOMAS
罗威尔·托马斯 世博会专题报道
Hello, everybody.
大家好
I'm Lowell Thomas.
我是罗威尔·托马斯
Standing in front one of what will soon be ...
在我身后就是即将成为 ......
... one of the wonders of the modern world.
...... 现代世界的奇观之一
When people asked me why did she stay.
当有人问我为什么她选择留下
Was it fear, lack of confidence?
是胆怯，还是没信心？
Margaret was trapped in the lie that she helped creat.
玛格丽特是被困在了自己添砖加瓦造成的谎言里
Another cover up is worth than a crime.
试图掩盖只会徒增罪孽罢了
Why did you have to promise them similar the size?
为什么你要跟他们允诺这么大尺幅的画作？
Because it has encompass all children, all races.
因为它可以装下所有种族、肤色的孩子
Hundreds of stricken faces marching to infinity.
成百上千受难的面孔走向无尽之地
The ultimate of the Walter Keane.
沃尔特·基恩的巅峰之作
A publicist says it's good timing to put out a coffee table book.
一个广告公关告诉我现在是时候推出一本茶几读物了
You know, Classy, Tomorrow's  Masters.
就是那种,时尚,明日大师之类的.
They need my early portfolio, artistic evolution.
他们需要一些我的早期画册，风格成型史什么的
Yes, where are all of your preliminary sketches?
对啊，你那些早期草图都在哪呢？
All that time you spent in art school seem to ...
你读美院大把的时间，应该积累下一叠叠早期的练习画册、各种碳笔草图什么的
Could be around here somewhere.
可能就在这附近吧，你找找
I know you been sarcastic, these are good idea.
我知道你只是说笑而与，我说的都是些好点子
Put in more orphans, early self portraits.
多加些孤儿进去，还有早期的自画像
Get out here, I'm try to work.
请出去吧，别打扰我工作
Mom, what about dinner?
妈，晚饭吃什么啊？
Mom, are you home?
妈，你在家吗？
Jane, this is Walter's studio, you need to leave.
简，这是沃尔特的画室，你快出去
Mom, I know.
妈，我知道
No, you don't know anything.
不，你啥都不知道
I'm not a child anymore.
我不再是小孩子了
Five... six pages. Is something here I missing?
五... 六页，我有漏了什么吗？
He's like the hula hoop, he just won't go away!
他就像呼啦圈，怎么都甩不掉！
" ... will be unveil in the grand pavilion of the hall of education ... "
"将会在教育馆的大厅揭幕"
" ... internationally celebrated artists been selected ... "
"享誉世界的艺术家被选作"
" ... will represent the aspiration of the children worldwide. "
"将代表全世界儿童的渴望 "
This is absurd!
荒谬！
Under who was on selection committee?
选举委员会都有哪些人？
Oh, there wasn't a committee precede.
哦，之前并不存在一个委员会
We just had luncheon, with me, Ed, and Jerome, Jerome's wife ...
只是我、艾德、杰罗姆和她的妻子办了个午宴而已 ...
Though technically we didn't invite submissions.
不过按章程我们不能邀请候选人
Mr. Keane just contact us directly.
基恩先生就直接给我们打了个电话
New York City, April. 1964
纽约市， 1964年四月
Come on.
高兴点嘛
Wednesday the World's Fair opens, Thursday our books on sell.
周三世博会开幕，周四我们的书开售
Friday I file for divorce.
周五我就申请离婚
Why are you always so miserable?
为什么你总要这么扫兴？
Well, I'm going to enjoy my afternoon.
我可要好好享受这个下午
Mrs. Tisdale, Walter Keane.
蒂斯代尔女士，鄙人沃尔特·基恩
I just want to thank you  for hosting this absolutely enchanting soiree.
我只想感谢你办的这个万分迷人的晚会
You're most welcome.
你太客气了
Keane, did you see the Times?
基恩，你看了纽约时报吗？
Honestly, I've been so busy all day preparing for this lovely occasion.
哪有功夫看，我一整天都在为这个重要场合忙上忙下的
I think you should read the Times.
我建议你还是去看一下
Art: World's Fair Pavilion Selects Theme Painting
世博会大厅主题画作选定基恩的作品
Appalling, grotesque, tasteless hack.
低劣，怪诞，画者毫无品味
How can somebody say something so cruel?
为什么有人能说出这么伤人的话？
Why do you care? this my name being drag through mud.
伤的是我的名誉，你干嘛要在乎？
Is he here?
他也在这？
Yes, which is perhaps why it's best for everybody if ...
在，或许大家最好都 ......
Who wrote this shit?
谁写的这篇狗屁文章？
Mr. Keane, this is not the venue.
基恩先生，这不是会议室
Perhaps you would like to write a letter to the editor?
或许你想给编辑写封信更合适吧？
What are you afraid of?
你在怕什么？
Just because people like my work, that means automatically it's bad?
就因为大众喜欢我的作品，所以必然意味着水准低？
No, but it doesn't make art either.
不一定，不过它也称不上是艺术
Art should elevate, not pander.
艺术应该是升华，而不是一味迎合
Particularly at the Hall of Education.
特别是挂在教育馆的作品
You have no idea!
你懂个屁！
Why does someone become a critic? because he can not creat.
为什么有人要去干评论？因为他不会动手只会动口
Oh dear, that mouldy chastener.
天啊，你只会说这种陈词滥调吗
Don't interrupt!
闭上你的狗嘴！
You don't know what's like to put your emotion out there, naked for the whole world to see!
你根本不能体会我倾注了多少情感进去，就好象赤身裸体的面对世人
What emotions? it's synthetic hack work.
哪来的情感？这水准就是烂大街的印刷品
Your "master piece" has infinite Keanes.
你的“大作”有无数的基恩
Which makes it infinite kitsch.
就代表低俗得无下限
What is wrong with the Lowest common denominator?
最低俗的人又怎么样？
That's what this country was build of!
这个国家不是靠这些人会有今天！
I'm gonna sue everybody.
我要把他们都告了
I'm gonna sue everybody!
要告他们每一个人！
I want to sue this pansy critic, sue the World's Fair.
我要告那个娘炮评论家，告世博会
I'm gonna take down Unicef, or his precous little box of dime.
我要扳倒联合国儿童基金会，断了他们的财路
But I can't sue you, can I?
不过我告不了你吧，是不是？
You're really ultimate betrayal, you fail me with that painting.
你才是最终黑手吧，用那幅画来整倒我
You cross over from sentimentality to kitsch.
你从多愁善感堕落成俗不可耐
Walter, stop it!
沃尔特，住手！
You like making me look bad, you enjoy people laughing at me?
你就想让我当众出丑，你就想看我被人笑话？
Open it up, open it up! let me in!
开门，快开门，让我进去！
I can see you!
我看得到你
I'm gonna burn you out!
我要烧死你！
You gonna blow up like atomic bomb!
让你尝尝原子弹爆炸的威力
Where are you?
你躲哪了?
I am so sorry, I was not the mother I could've been.
我对不起你，我不是个合格的母亲
I should've done this years ago.
多年前我就该这么做的
Can't believe we're going, We don't have any clothes.
我们真的要走吗，连衣服都没带
Where we're going, we don't need much!
我们要去的地方，不需多少衣服
Hawaii.
夏威夷
Really?
真的？
Yes, Hawaii, because it's paradise there.
恩，去夏威夷，因为那里是天堂
You know there're birds, flowers, beautiful colours.
你会见识那的鸟语花香，风景秀丽
We gonna make a new life for ourselves.
我们会开启一段新的人生
That's my girl.
我的乖女儿
Honolulu, One year later.
火奴鲁鲁, 一年后
You're sure hard to track down, I thought I may never find you.
你躲得真够远的啊，我还以为再也见不到你了
Walter ...
沃尔特 ......
I was a little agitated.
我有点烦躁
I got this strangest paper in the mail today.
今天我收到一封从未见过的信
It's a decreed legal seperation, I would appreciated it if you sign it.
那是法定分居协议书，我会很感激你把它签了
Aren't you acting a little rush?
你难道不觉得这事急了点吗？
Walter, I want a divorce.
沃尔特，我想要离婚
Hurts to hear you say these words, that's sure how we come to this.
你说的话让人难过，没想到我们也会有这一天
I suppose I could agree just split as long as...
你想分居多久我都可以答应，只要你今后作的每一幅画都签我的名字
If that's the price.
那成交
Really?
你真的同意？
Ok, well, then we have to consider future revenue strings ...
那就好，那么我们还得商讨下将来的收入问题
My God, Walter! how much more money do you need?
老天，沃尔特！你要赚多少钱才满意？
If you want me out of your life, here is my bargain.
如果你想摆脱我，就仔细听好了
You have to paint me a hundred more waifs ...
你得给我画上百张孤儿上百张签有沃尔特·基恩的画
Jane, I'm gonna go to post stop, you wanna come?
简，我要去趟邮局，想跟我一起吗？
No, I'm gonna go surf's game.
不了，我想去冲浪
- Jane, I think your friends are a little wild. - Who's not, mom?
简，我觉得你的朋友都有点野 谁不是啊，老妈？
You're impossible.
你有点不可理喻
You move all the way ...
我们大老远的搬到夏威夷来，我这才交上几个朋友，可你动不动就发他们的牢骚
Maybe you need to make some.
也许你得交几个朋友了
You know that I can not have people over to the house.
你知道我不可以让人来家里的
That's right, or else they would see the precious paintings.
那倒是，不然他们会看到你的宝贝画作
Hello, we visit everyone in this neighbourhood with an important message.
你好，我们在这附近挨家挨户的传递一条重要信息
We have something to share with you ..
我们想跟你分享一些关于上帝的王国会给人类带来的福祉
Well from where I'm standing, I don't see much good anywhere ...
那在我待的地方，我没看到多少好事
... just a lot of pride deviant people treating each other poorly.
尽是些斯文败类互相算计对方
Do you know what it says in Timothy 3: 1-5?
你知道提摩太后书3章1至5节吗？
In the last days, critical time hard to dealt with will be here ...
末世必有危险的日子来到
... for men would be lovers of themselves.
因为那时人要专顾自己
Sounds like my ex-husband.
听起来像我前夫
Would you like to come in?
你们想进来吗？
It says right here, "a worshiper of Jehovah must be honest in all things".
这里说了，“耶和华的信徒必须事事诚实”
I just can't believe you let people in the house.
我只是不敢相信你让人进我们家了
It also says, "No lies speak the truth, let stealer steal no more."
这还说了，“谎言替代不了真相，愿窃贼改邪归正”
Shit, this is crazy man! all these copies! you're like Worhol!
你可真酷啊，这么多印刷品，你就像安迪·沃霍尔!
Worhol like me.
沃霍尔像我还差不多
That fruit fly stole my art.
那个讨厌鬼都是偷我的
My art supplies!
我的新货到了！
I had a factory ...
我开工厂的时候浓汤罐头还没出现呢！
Oh yeah, we got a special guest today.
太棒了，今天我们这里来了位特别的客人
A  world famous celebrity.
一位世界级的名人
So let's give a big 'Aloha' to Margaret Keane.
下面让我们热烈欢迎玛格丽特·基恩
So, is it true you husband Walter is the top selling painter in the world?
这是真的吗，你丈夫沃尔特是世界上最畅销的画家之一？
No, big Lolo, everything you just said is false.
不，大罗罗，刚才你说的每个字都是错的
One, Walter and I are no longer married.
首先，我和沃尔特已经离婚了
And two, he is not a painter.
其次，他不是位画家
But did I mistake, is he the guy does the 'crazy eyes'?
难道我搞错了，不是他画的大眼睛吗？
No.
不是
Although he's been taking credit for 10 years.
尽管他已经被认可了10年
I am the only painter in family.
可我才是家里唯一的画家
You got to be kidding!
这不是开玩笑吧！
You know what piss me off?
你知道什么让我很不爽吗？
Margaret give the scoop to some button pusing Big Lolo.
玛格丽特把爆炸新闻送给只会按按钮的大罗罗
Instead of some respectful jounalist like myself.
而不是像我这种受人尊敬的记者
I knew it.
我就知道
Who were the waif craft?
谁才是孤儿画家？
Margaret gone berserk, you got to help me.
玛格丽特发疯了，你得帮我一把
I need a story, wire story, national, just to calm things down.
我需要篇文章，上全国广播，给这事降降温
I don't know, Walter. which she said is pretty inflammatory.
我不清楚，沃尔特，她说的内容相当有煽动性啊
This is nuts, doesn't even make sense!
这都是疯话，根本讲不通！
When I studied art at Beaux Arts at the Paris,  she was still a little kid in Tennessee!
我在巴黎就读法兰西艺术院时，她还是个田纳西的小P孩呢！
Look.
看看这
My very sketches.
我的草图册
Berlin orphans, 1949.
1949年，柏林孤儿
Why would Margaret do something like that?
玛格丽特为什么要这么做？
She's unhinge. she left me to move into the jungle.
她崩溃了，离开我搬到丛林里
Fell in with religious zealous.
接受宗教狂热分子的洗脑
Jehovah's witness.
耶和华见证会
I really don't know all that much about that.
我真的不太了解那些东西
They don't celebrate Christmas, can't salute to flag.
她们不过圣诞节，也不向国旗敬礼
They won't even let Jane go to the prom.
她们甚至不准简去参加毕业舞会
He makes me sound crazy.
他让我看上去像个疯子
He said I copy him, he taught me how to paint.
他不但说我抄袭他，还说他教的我绘画
"She use a slide projector to trace my work and fill in the colors"
"她用一台幻灯机来临摹我的画，然后再填上颜色”
Which part of that isn't true?
有哪些部分不是真的？
All of  it!
全都不是真的！
I feel good about myself for the first time in years, I can't let Walter ...
这么些年来我第一次为自己感到骄傲，我不会让沃尔特把尊严也夺走
Is Jehovah ok with suing?
耶和华不反对上法庭吧？
U.S. Federal District Court Honolulu Reporter: $ 17.000.000.
美国联邦地方法庭， 火奴鲁鲁 记者：一千七百万美元
The art world is a buzz.
艺术圈炸开了锅
Today at federal court, lawyers will present their opening argument ...
今天在联邦法院，控辩双方律师将提交开案陈词
... indicate Magaret Keane vs. Walter Keane and Gkanet newspaper ...
标志着玛格丽特·基恩对阵沃尔特·基恩和堪内特新闻集团案的开始
... a trial could produce largest libel and slander reward in Hawaii histories.
判决有可能产生夏威夷史上最大宗的文字和口头诽谤罚金
Step aside, please.
请让一下
Mr. Keane, are you at all concerns about the charges?
基恩先生，你担不担心指控成立？
I am angry as hell, but I'm lucky I have the mighty Gkanet news company watching my back.
我对指控十分愤怒，不过幸运的是我有强大的凯内特新闻集团做我的后盾
I expect this whole trial dismissed by noon.
我预计整个案子中午就会被驳回
My only concern is somebody give this women some psychiatric help, she needs it.
我唯一担忧的是有没有心理医师给这个女人提供点帮助，她病得不轻
All right, excuse me, gentle man, excuse me.
好了，请让一下，大家都请让下
Margaret Keane is a public figure ...
玛格丽特·基恩作为一个公众人物
... and such him has approve that our newspaper's public statements  ...
尽管知道可能的不实，却从未对我们发表的公开内容提出任何质疑
Now there is not evidence to suggest our editors could've known these assertion were untrue.
目前未有证据能表明我们的编辑事先知道这些声明并不属实
We would like to submit 692 articles and interviews in which Mrs. Keane ...
我们想提交692页相关文章以及访问稿，基恩女士
... credits Mr. Keane as the painter of the so call "Big Eyes Children".
在每一篇里都肯定基恩先生是“大眼睛孤儿”的创作者
How many years back these go?
这些最早追溯到哪一年？
Mrs. Keane has been making these statement since 1958.
基恩女士从1958年就开始作那些声明了
This is very strange case.
这个案子非常离奇
These paintings hanging museums all over the world all tribute to Mr. Keane.
这些挂在世界各地博物馆里的画作全都归属于基恩先生捐赠
And regardless of the truth, Mrs. Keane has contributed immeasurably to the comfusion.
不管真相到底如何，基恩女士对这乱成一团的案情负有相当大的责任
It seems impossible to connect such action would ever meet the standard of libel..
看起来被告人的行为是不可能构成文字诽谤的
So the charge againts them is dismissed.
因此驳回对新闻集团的上诉
Thank you, Your Honor.
谢谢，法官大人
Good luck, Keane.
祝你好运，基恩
Good luck? where're you going?
祝我好运？你要去哪？
We're charged with libel, you're charged with slander.
我们被诉文字诽谤，你被诉口头诽谤
Mr. Keane?
基恩先生？
You appear to be without consult.
你现在没律师了
Would you like to post permit in order to get your fair and orders?
你想要像法庭申请一个吗？
I've always taken care of myself, I don't need a bunch of rented suits ...
我一直以来都靠的是自己，不需要找那些律师来为我的清白辩护
Let's proceed.
让我们继续吧
I concern about my old pal Walter Keane.
我很担心老交情沃尔特·基恩
The Hawaii heat may cook his brain.
夏威夷的酷热可能会让他失去理智
The only thing he knows about court room and laws come from watching Perry Mason on televison.
他对法庭和法律的唯一了解就是来自电视剧佩里·梅森
I am the sole creator of my art.
我是我艺术品的唯一作者
This is my entire life, my contribution to the world.
那就是我的整个人生和对世界的贡献
Mr. Keane, I told you, you must ask witness questions.
基恩先生，我刚才说了，你现在必须提问证人
If you acting as your own attorney, you can not make statement this time.
如果你要做你自己的律师，现在不是你的陈述时间
Alright.
知道了
It's hard to keep all these things straight.
要把这一切理顺还是有点难度
Mrs. Keane, how did you expect anybody to swallow your fantastic story?
基恩女士，你怎么能指望别人接受你那幻想出来的故事？
Mr. Keane!
基恩先生！
Mrs. Keane, you seems to be lucid, reasonablely intelligent woman.
基恩女士，你似乎是个明事理，辨是非的知识女性
So how could you possibly have gone along with far-out statement like that?
那么你怎么可能要去炮制这样没道理的故事？
I feel forced into it.
我觉得被逼无奈
You have me ...
你让我 ......
He had me dominated.
他掌控了我
He would rant and rave if I don't give he what he wanted.
如果我不满足他的要求就会被他骂得胆战心惊
I was afraid, and I didn't see any options, so I went along.
我很害怕，也看不到任何出路，因此就从了他
May I remind you that you're under the oath?
我想提醒下你可是宣过誓的
I just give in, I allow him to take credit for the "Big Eyes".
我于是就屈服了，默许他把据为己有
They were the reflection of my feelings, and  it was like losing a child.
它们代表着我的情感，那种感觉好似失去了亲骨肉
But I was weak.
可是我太懦弱
I didn't think I can live and surpport myself and my daughter.
我不认为自己带着女儿能有一份像样的人生
And he said nobody would buy the paintings without his personality.
而且他说要不是靠他的个人魅力，我的画会无人问津
Maybe he was right.
也许他有对的地方
You were very talented been charming, and you're a genius at sale and promotion.
你很会引人注目，也是销售和推广的天才
It sounds like you're describing two different man.
听上去你好像描述得是两个人啊
One a sadistic ogre, the other one a delightful bon vivant.
一个是可怕的魔鬼，另一个却是讨喜的上流绅士
That's you, Walter, you're Jekyll and Hyde.
那正是你，沃尔特，你就像化身博士
That's outrageous statement! I demand we strike it out from the record.
那是恶语中伤！我要求法庭记录将其删去
Overrule!
驳回！
You were outrageous, constantly criticise me, wore me down ...
你才是恶语中伤，总是指责我，让我疲于应对威胁我说如果我说出真相就杀了我
Well, I'm telling the truth.
可我现在说的就是真相
Your Honor!
法官大人！
I asks for mistrial.
请求未决审判
You're a liar, you don't even know what the truth is!
你是个骗子，你的字典里根本就没有真话二字！
You don't even know, but I'm stating the truth now.
你根本就没有, 而我现在能说出真相
You can not shut me up!
你没法让我噤声！
This is not a domestic squabble, or maybe it is.
这不是一场家庭口角，或许说晚了点
But the rest of us have no interest in watching you two go at it.
不过我们剩下的人可没兴趣看你俩吵下去
I'm sorry for my emotion.
我很抱歉失态了
I'm a artist.
我是位艺术家
Maybe.
也许吧
Your Honor!
法官大人！
I call as my witness, Mr. Walter Stanley Keane!
我现在请出我的证人，沃尔特·斯坦利·基恩先生！
You swear to tell the truth, the whole truth, nothing but the truth, so help you God?
你发誓所说一切属实，绝无半点隐瞒和谎言，愿上帝保佑你?
Yes.
是的
Mr. Keane, there seems a lot of in your window and contradictory testimony about the genesis of the "Big Eye Waifs"
基恩先生，似乎对于“大眼睛孤儿”的起源有很多风言风语和矛盾百出的证词
Would you mind clarify to this court who spawn these paintings?
你能不能向法庭澄清是谁创作了这些画？
Why, I created these children.
为什么，是我创作的这些孤儿画
Choreography is not necessary, Just sit down and testify.
法庭不是你表演的舞台，坐好了说
I had a wonderful life.
我的人生丰富多彩
I was a artist, and friend of untold celebrities.
作为一名艺术家，数不清的名人争着做我朋友
Yeah, when I look back at all ...
然而，当我蓦然回首这一生发现做过最重要的事就是为世界上的孤儿尽了些微薄之力
It all began in Berlin, after World War II ...
一切始于柏林，二战后
The orphans clutching part of wire, their bodies lacerated ...
那些满是伤痕的孤儿紧紧抓住铁网 ......
... their fingers scrawny ... their eyes big.
小手如同干柴 大大的眼睛
Mrs. Joan Crawford walked out ...
琼·克劳福德女士走出
Mr. Keane, sit down.
基恩先生，请坐好
Marilyn Monroe ...
玛丽莲·梦露
the Newton and I ...
我和牛顿
Jerry Lewis calls me says I wants you to paint me and my family in clown suits.
杰里·刘易斯打电话请我画他们全家身着小丑服的样子
Mrs. Natalie Wood walked out to me and said ...
娜塔莉·伍德女士走过来对我说
"This is the greatest single painting I've ever seen in my entire life!"
"这是我一生当中见过画的最美的一幅画！"
You done!
你不用说了！
- I'm not finished. - Actually you are!
我还没说完呢 这我说了算！
I can not stand one more wire or shaggy dog tale.
我实在是受不了你那些故作煽情、冗长无趣的故事了
You're not testify, you filibuster it.
你根本不是在作证，完全是在捣乱
Federal court overburden enough without you ducky clacking nonsense.
不需要你的那些废话，联邦法庭就已经不堪重负了
We can stay here until we grow old and die ...
我们可以在这耗到死不过这个案子很明显就是你和基恩女士各执一词
Mistrial.
未决审判
No, it's not a mistrial!
不，这不会是未决审判！
In my opinion, there is only one way to clear this thing up.
以我的观点，只有一个办法可以找出真相
You're both going to paint!
你们俩都作一幅画！
All right, bring those easels down, set them up on both side of the bench.
好了，把画架搬过来，摆在两边的椅子旁
Now I'm not looking for a master piece.
先说下我不需要什么大作
I'm don't know much about these things, I'm a amateur, not art critic.
我对这些了解不多，业余水准，也当不了评论家
But is one hour enough?
不过1个小时够了吧?
Yes, Your Honor.
恩，法官大人
Ok, then.
那么好
You both been provided with identical supplies.
给你们俩都提供了相同的器具
So, without any further business, Mrs. Keane, Mr. Keane. the court is yours.
那么，没有其他事的话，基恩女士，基恩先生，法庭交给你们了
Mr. Keane?
基恩先生?
Just setting them.
只是平心静气
Waiting for the muse to strike.
等候灵感出现
Well, your muse has 58 minutes.
那好吧，你的灵感还有58分钟
Mr. Keane, are you alright?
基恩先生，你没事吧？
My old shoulder injury just flare up a bad muscle.
我肩膀的旧伤又犯了，肌肉拉伤
I've been taking medicationg for inflammation ...
我一直有吃消炎药
I don't think I will be able to paint today.
我想今天是没法动笔了
The jury found a favour with Margaret Keane on all points.
陪审团裁定玛格丽特·基恩的各项控诉成立
She went on charges of defamation, emotional destress, and damaged reputation.
她要继续提出诽谤、情感伤害、名誉侵害等指控
Congratulation... Margaret ...
祝贺你 玛格丽特
Thank you, thank you very much.
谢谢大家，非常感谢
Margaret, what do you going to call the painting?
玛格丽特，你要给这幅画起个什么名字？
exhibit 224.
非卖品224号
Margaret, can I possibly have your autograph?
玛格丽特，能给我签个名吗？
Two things matter to Margaret.
两件事对玛格丽特最为重要
Her daughter and her paintings.
她的画和女儿
And after all the crazy turn the story took ...
在经历了各种风风雨雨后
... she came out the end with bountiful.
她终于见到彩虹
Walter never accepted defeat.
沃尔特从未承认失败
Insisting he was the true artist for the rest of his life.
此后一直坚称自己才是真正的艺术家
He died in 2000, bitter and penniless.
2000年，他在痛苦和潦倒中逝去
He never produced another painting.
他也再未画过一幅画
Margaret found personal happiness and remarried.
玛格丽特从拾快乐并再婚
After many years in Hawaii, she moved back to San Franciso.
在夏威夷待了多年后，她又搬回了旧金山
And opened a new gallery.
并开了新画廊
She still paints everyday.
她仍坚持创作